Ted Eriksson

07794740496 ted.eriksson@me.com

Online Portfolio: http://tederiksson.github.io

Personal Statement

A highly confident, positive and energetic graduate with a First Class BSc Computer Science degree from Oxford Brookes University. Can easily work well with a team to produce clean and readable code. Primarily a Java developer with experience in Android development. Genuinely excited about computing and expanding skills in a professional environment.

Education

Oxford Brookes University (2011 - 2014)

First Class BSc Computer Science

Key Modules:

- Advanced Object-Oriented Programming
- Advanced Mobile Software Development
- Requirements Specification and Software Design
- · Algorithms and Advanced Data Structures
- Web Technology

Java Android Design Patterns C++ HTML5 CSS3 Javascript/jQuery

Sussex Downs College, Lewes (2009 - 2011)

A-Level Maths B A-Level Physics C A-Level Computing C AS Photography C

Ringmer Community College (2008 - 2009)

11 GCSEs A-C Grade

Experience

Points of Interest (September 2013 - May 2014)

For my undergraduate dissertation, I created a Points of Interest style Android application. It created a RESTful web API to store system data. Other technologies used included Augmented Reality and NFC.

Android PHP Design Patterns RESTful API's

Ted's Webs (2012 - Present)

Developer and Project Manager

I created Ted's Webs in 2012 as a web design company, since then we have produced anything from small portfolio websites to large in-house management systems.

Currently my associate and I are finishing a contract for a major private aviation company. We have built an in-house management system from the ground up, that allows them to streamline their workflow and save costs. I acted as project manager and UI designer.

HTML5 CSS3 PHP MySQL Javascript/jQuery

Fotobox Ltd. (January 2013 and June 2013 - August 2013)

Web Developer

I restructured their iPhone Application server to increase performance, add features and integrate Amazon Web Services to create a scalable web app. I redesigned their website to bring it up to todays standards. I occasionally worked in the shop interacting with customers.

Amazon Web Services HTML5 CSS3 PHP MySQL Javascript/jQuery

EBS Ltd. (2008-2011)

Decorator and Labourer

I worked on various building sites as a decorator and labourer. Through this, I improved my people skills and work ethic

Work Ethic

Interests and Hobbies

- Cooking/hosting dinner parties
- Golf and tennis (casual)
- Ukulele
- Learning and keeping up to date with new technologies